Nicholas Cerisano

Toronto, Ontario | cell: 416-556-4060 | ncerisano@gmail.com

STUDENT PROFILE

A talented, creative, and results-driven student software developer with top marks in programming due to high proficiency in coding across multiple programming languages. High self-initiative to continually learn about innovations in software development. Strong leadership and interpersonal skills with experience working with diverse groups.

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Strong interpersonal communication skills honed through formal competitive debate and public speaking, as well as through teamwork with many diverse school and work teams
- Highly proficient in C# and Java; proficient in JavaScript, TypeScript, C, C++, Python, Go, F#, and MATLAB programming languages; SQL, as well as HTML and CSS markup languages.
- Knowledgeable in the frameworks: Docker, Spring Boot, Redux, React, Bootstrap, Xamarin, SQLite
- Highly knowledgeable in Unity Engine and GIMP for the creation of games and game art
- Strong project management skills; efficiently delegates, organizes and manages tasks during team projects to consistently meet work requirements and deliver on time
- Proficient in Microsoft Office suite
- Life Saving Society Certified Lifeguard, Swim/Lifesaving/Emergency First Aid Instructor
- Certified in Standard First Aid and CPR-C

EDUCATION

York University | September 2018 – to date | Second Year

- Computer Science Program: courses include: First order logic, Theory of Computation, Algorithm design, C programming, Database Systems, and Computer Organization
- Recipient of York University Entrance Scholarship

Chaminade College School | June 2018 | Diploma & STEM Certificate

- STEM program (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math)
- Honour Roll Student
- Clubs: Chaminade Model UN, Reach for the Top, Chess, Debate Team

EXTRACURRICULAR DEVELOPMENT

I spend a lot of my free time growing as a programmer. My initial inspiration was gaming; I spent time learning about game design, game engine design and the underlying math.

C# Unity Developer 2D: Learn to Code Making Games

Udemy 2018

Projects I have completed within the Udemy course include a Space Infesters game (in the likeness of Galaga), and a tower defense game (in the likeness of Plants vs. Zombies), called "Glitch Garden." I am currently developing a rogue-like set in space.

- Space Infesters: https://github.com/EpicNicks/SpaceInfesters
- Plants vs. Zombies clone: https://github.com/EpicNicks/Glitch Garden

Personal Projects

Projects I have created on my own include a 2D "Infinite Runner" game, and a "Hangman" game that I created as an enhancement for a grade 12 project entitled "Game Day."

Games made in the Unity Engine followed by their GitHub URL:

- **Infinite Runner**: https://github.com/EpicNicks/Infinite-Runner
- Hangman: created to experiment with a user editable .json file, https://github.com/EpicNicks/GameDay

Other non-Unity projects include a portfolio website I created with the React framework, using the TypeScript programming language; a Discord bot written in Python 3 I dubbed 'New Fork', a tongue-incheek reference to York University's most infamous joke, which allows users on a Discord server to participate in an online virtual economy and play games impacting said economy.

Portfolio Site:

- Website URL: https://epicnicks.github.io/nicholas-cerisano-resume,
- o GitHub repo: https://github.com/EpicNicks/nicholas-cerisano-resume
- New Fork Discord Bot: https://github.com/EpicNicks/new-fork-discord-bot

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Intern | Moneris | May 2019 – August 2019

Responsible for Quality Assurance testing of the Moneris Risk Database (MRD) website. I coded test cases that performed regression tests to simulate/replace a human QA tester. The regression tests are written in is JavaScript using the frameworks Jest and Puppeteer.

- Wrote asynchronous JavaScript code for use in test cases.
- Performed manual testing and bug reporting on the MRD project's GitLab page.
- Maintained my own GitLab branch dedicated to automation testing.

Swim Instructor and Lifeguard | City of Toronto | December 2016 – to date

Responsible for the aquatic education and assessment of children and adults in private to large classes. As a lifeguard, I am responsible for interfacing with and the safety of all swimmers, including preserving the public image of City of Toronto Aquatics.

- Teach swimming and lifesaving standards to people of all ages. Complete assessments and share outcomes with the swimmers and for City of Toronto administrative records.
- Create learning plans to facilitate efficient classes within periods of 15 minutes to 2 hours.
- Perform rescues on victims in teams with other lifeguards under pressure, administered first aid for major to minor incidents.
- Ensure City of Toronto safety standards are adhered to including closing duties, pool chlorination, reporting incidents and proper ratio of children to guardians are met.
- Participate in seasonal and annual lifeguard, swim instruction and first-aid training to keep current with Lifesaving Society and City of Toronto standards.

Aquatics Lifeguard | Cedar Fair - Canada's Wonderland | June 2016 - August 2016

Responsible for the safe and efficient operation of water attractions while providing professional lifeguarding. In addition, to provide guest service and assistance in a hospitable manner to address gueries regarding the Aquatics area and the overall park.

- Responsible for the safety of riders and ensured they were dispatched and exited safely
- Performed rescues on drowning victims for catch-pools and at the Lazy River.
- Accountable for closing duties that included tabulating and submitting guest count sheets by the hour and tidying up at the end of the day.
- Participate in and pass bi-weekly training assessments to meet Ellis Lifeguard and Canada's Wonderland requirements and standards.

OTHER INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- Creating games, Watching videos on advanced computer programming
- Reading textbooks and write-ups on different complex computer programs such as compilers
- Competitive sports and activities including swimming, playing hockey, baseball, paintball
- Participate in competitive card tournaments